

# PROFILE

me@lemosl.com.br

C/C++, JS, SQL, Bash, Linux

+55 41 99618-8104

System Development Engineer @ Siemens | Software Developer



https://lemosl.com.br

With over five years of work experience, I'm a passionate developer that learned life is much more than coding. Working with international teams since 2016, I really believe in the diversity and talent that a remote

From low-level backend optimization to the UI & UX. I enjoy navigating the end to end spectrum of skills that a real-world solution requires so the well stablished silos of knowledge can be minimized.

environment brings to the table.

#### HARD SKILLS

C++SOL Linux C Javascript Bash

#### SOFT SKILLS

Leadership Communication Troubleshooting **Problem Solving** 

# TOOLS & SERVICES

Gitlab Docker Vim CI/CD GDB

#### **EXPERIENCES**

O System Development Engineer

Lucas Lemos

Siemens / Curitiba-BR / 2021 - Present (3 years) Data Modeling of CIM-based application in a framework built on top of Oracle, C++, Perl and Bash scripts. I'm involved in bug fixing, new features design and tightening the gap with other teams (SysAdmins, UI and System

**SIEMENS** 

Junior System Development Engineer Siemens / Curitiba-BR / 2018-2020 (2 years) Joined a team that developed from the ground up a Self-Healing solution for the Distribution grid. Using internal technologies for the back and frontend, I became the "oneman band" that implemented features and talked to customers



**⊙** Intern – R&D

Architects)

TDK InvenSense / Grenoble-FR / 2018 (6 months) Developed a project to use an array of microphones to detect a sound source in 3D space. Started from researching academic papers in the literature to building a prototype of an MVP solution.



Intern – Researcher GIPSA Lab / Grenoble-FR/ 2017 (3 months) I worked on a visual perception bio-inspired model to categorize natural vs. artificial images. An image was classified with a set of filter to mimic how human brain works. We experimented with classic image classification algorithms to understand how far it could go.



## EDUCATION

Masters in Embedded System Polytech Grenoble 🗾 / 2016-2018



Embedded System Engineer UFPR Curitiba ■ / 2012-2018



### LANGUAGES

English French Portuguese